≪重
That's heavy!
(嶋田)うお上がた
(内沢)ナイスフォロ
It's up!
Nice save!
So please, call for a set just one more time...
(西谷)だからもう一回
トスを呼んでくれエス
ace!
(菅原)嶋田さん
(東峰)スガ
Shimada!
Suga!
One more!
もう一本
(菅原)旭
Asahi!
(一同)おお
(武田)うひゃ
What a sound!
ドゴゴて
It went ka-doom!
(菅原)
ナイスナイス旭西谷も
Nice! Good job, Asahi!
You too, Nishinoya!
お前らもナイストススガ
You guys too. Nice set, Suga.
西谷もナイスレシブ
Nishinoya, nice receive.
(日向翔陽)
あれがあれがエス
That's the ace.
Hey.
エス見たい見たいて
言てたろうが
You're the one who wanted to see the ace.
Don't freak out!
ビビてんじゃねぇぞ
ビビビてねぇよ
I-I'm not freaking out!
あんなふうに
身長もパワもないけど
I don't have his height or power, but I can fight too.
俺だて戦える
次は俺の番だ
I'll be him next!
(菅原)≪手のひら一枚
厚さ約２センチ
The width of a hand is approximately 2 cm.
同年代の連中と比べても
ひと回り小さな手≫
My hands are slightly smaller than anyone in my own age group.
The 2 cm between the ball and the floor...
(菅原)≪この
ボルと床の間２センチが
(菅原)≪エスの命を
can keep the ace...
繋ぐんだ≫
alive.
全然ジャンプ
できてないじゃないですか
You can't jump worth a damn!
Episode Ten:
The Dream
１か月もサボるから
(東峰)うんすみません
Skipping practice for a month will do that!
Yeah. I'm sorry.
(菅原)ふふ厳しいなぁ西谷
(田中)はは
Harsh, Nishinoya.
大地さん
(澤村)うん
Daichi!
Yeah!
でもベテランの町内会組に加えて
旭も復活てなると
If Asahi is back and we're facing both him and this veteran team,
いよいよ俺たちが厳しいぞ
we're gonna have trouble winning this.
へへへ
何言てんすか大地さん
What're you talking about, Daichi? You've got me on your si—
こちには俺が
こちには俺がいますよ
You've got me on your side!
Huh? What?
え何
日向かぶてんじゃねぇよ
Hinata, butt out!
You've ruined my awesome speech, you idiot!
せかくの俺のカｯコいいセリフが
ぐだぐだだよバカ野郎
いやすごい
西谷君のレシブも
That was great!
And Nishinoya's receive was awesome!
ブロｯクされたボルが拾えるなら
怖いものなしですね
If we can retrieve blocked balls, we have nothing to fear!
(繋心)
何言てんだあんなもん
As if.
He can't retrieve those all the time.
毎回拾えるわけねぇだろ
え
Huh?
(繋心)１００キロか
それ以上のスピドのボルが
The ball plummets down at a speed of
100 km/h from just 2 or 3 meters away.
ほんの２３メトルの
至近距離から落ちてくるんだ
There's no way he can retrieve every one.
そんなもん全部拾えるわけねぇ
おお
ただ
Right.
The important thing is to get it into their heads that a blocked ball isn't the end of the world.
ブロクされたらそこで
おしまいてわけじゃないと
分かてることが大事なんだ
I'm gonna retrieve 'em like crazy, so please keep getting blocked!
後ろには
ちゃんと仲間がいるんだと
You get a whole new frame of mind once you know you've got teammates backing you up.
分かてるかどうかで
気持ちは全然違うもんさ
What?
Nah, an ace will score every time.
(武田)なるほど
(森)ナイサ
I see!
What?!
Karasuno        Neighborhood Assoc.
Give us a good one!
ピ
(澤村)縁下
Ennoshita!
(縁下)あ
カバ
Cover it!
On the whole, their receives still need work.
≪レシブは
全体的にまだまだだな≫
Sorry, Kageyama. Cover it!
はい
≪落下地点の見極めが早い≫
Got it!
He quickly and decisively gauges distance and the point of impact.
≪迷いのない１歩目
こちのセｯタは確か１年か
If I remember correctly, this setter is a first-year.
さあこから誰を使
The question is, which one will I put in the line—
(２人)あ
ピ
(田中)ナイス日向影山
Nice, Hinata, Kageyama!
(２人)あぁ
あざす
Thank you!
((今はこいつのトスがあるから
But now, with this guy setting for me, I can evade any block, no matter how high it may be.
どんな高いブロクも
かわせます))
大げさなこと言てるわけじゃ
なかたんだな
He wasn't exaggerating.
That's amazing, Shouyou!
すげぇじゃねぇか翔陽
なんだなんだ
What was that?! I couldn't help but watch!
うかり見入ちゃたぞ
えへへへ
≪サイン出してるわけでも
なかたし
They didn't make any kind of visible or vocal signal, so how?!
声も掛けてないのに
おい
え
Boy!
今なんでそこに跳んでた
ちんちくりん
Why did you jump over there just now, Peewee?!
Peewee?
B-Because the set will come to me no matter where I am... sir.
どどこにいても
トスが来るからです
≪明らかに今ちんちくりんは
It's obvious the peewee jumped without looking for the set.
トスを見ずに跳んでいた
この１年セタは
ちんちくりんの動きに
Does this first-year setter completely adapt to the peewee's every action?!
完全に合わせたのか
≪それにトスが来るからて
なんで言い切れるんだ
And how can he be so sure that the set will come to him?!
≪それだけで
全くトスを見ないで
Does anyone in their right mind go all-out on a set without looking?!
フルスイングできるか普通
(繋心)なんだお前ら変人か
え
What are you guys, deviants?!
(２人)変人
なんで
Deviants?
How come?
知るか
(月島)ふふ
Beats me.
Tsukishima, wipe that grin off your face!
試合前のやり取りで
なんのことか分かんなかたが
I have no idea what they were discussing before the match...
(菅原)((圧倒的な実力の
影山の陰に隠れて
I hid in the shadow of Kageyama's overwhelming talent.
安心してたんだ
It was comfortable there.
(繋心)あの１年セタは
まあ天才てやつなんだろう
That first-year setter has to be what they call a prodigy.
Hinata, we're gonna nail another.
Right!
Normal mortals pale in comparison to him.
それと比べられたら凡人は
たまたもんじゃないが
You can do this!
However...
(嶋田)おお平行
Ooh, a straight spike.
God damn, his timing is bang-on even after being out for a month!
１か月ぶりでも
タイミングばちりだな
ちくしょうめ
田中喜びすぎ
Tanaka, you're too happy.
トスとスパイクの
一瞬の呼吸
The one breath between the set and the spike.
そりゃたくさんの練習と
積み重ねた時間があるから
It can only be achieved over time with lots of training.
できること
(菅原)うし
Yes!
(繋心)あの信頼関係は
一朝一夕で築けるもんじゃない
Their bond of trust cannot be built in a day.
１年セタにあるのが
圧倒的才能だとしたら
So if the first-year setter's weapon is overwhelming talent,
こちは積み重ねた信頼と安定
then that means his weapon is
accumulated trust and consistency.
ふ
え
(澤村)オライ
I got it!
いいじゃねぇか今の烏野
Karasuno ain't such a bad team!
ぎ
もと早く言えよ先生
You should've told me sooner, teach.
I did tell you, many times.
何回も言いましたよ僕
(澤村･田中･日向)よしゃ
Karasuno        Neighborhood Assoc.
Yes!
Who'd have thought that Peewee could be a middle blocker?
それにしてもあのちんちくりんが
ミドルブロカとはねぇ
速攻は確かにすごいけど
ブロクはどうだ
His fast attacks are impressive, but how does he block?
≪なんか見てる
I'm being watched.
(武田)
おおそういえばこの試合
That's right! This match is Hinata's showdown against his dream ace.
日向君は
憧れのエスと対決なんですねぇ
あ
日向君はね
Huh?
You see, Hinata enrolled in Karasuno because he wants to be just like the ace they called "The Little Giant."
小さな巨人と呼ばれてた
エスに憧れて
この烏野に来たらしいんですよ
(繋心)へえあいつにか
Who, him?
だからエスになるて言て
いつも頑張てるんですよ
So that's why he tries so hard. He says he's gonna be the ace.
そんな日向君が烏野の現エスと
直接対決てわけです
For Hinata, this is his big face-off against the current ace of Karasuno.
ほぉ面白ぇじゃんか
Really? That sounds fun.
Although it's more like man versus junior high school student.
社会人対中学生みたいだけどな
あはは
≪平行≫
Straight.
≪俺今エスをマクしてる≫
Right now, I'm marking the ace.
≪烏野のエスと戦てる≫
I'm fighting against the ace of Karasuno!
Give us a good serve!
ピ
(縁下)ナイサ
(滝ノ上)ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
≪あという間に目の前に
A split-second later, he's right in front of me!
ピ
Karasuno        Neighborhood Assoc.
I was aware of how high he could jump,
but it's more impressive when he's at eye level.
(東峰)
すごく跳ぶのは分かてたけど
I'm sorry!
目の前に来ると
本当にすごいな
Shake it off!
You almost had it.
一体
どのくらい跳んでるんだあれ
How high is the guy jumping?
Save it for next time!
Yes, sir!
He's amazing, and he hasn't played for a month!
すごい
１か月ぶりのはずなのに
Not bad, Asahi.
お前ブロクのとき
手の出し方が悪い
You're holding your hands wrong when you block!
止めるつもりならこうこうだ
This is how you block! Like this!
聞いてんのかこうだ
Are you listening? Like this!
Get the next one too.
(菅原)次も頼むぞ
おい
Hey!
≪汗いぱいで苦しそうで
He was sweaty and hurting,
but the Little Giant never stopped jumping.
≪でも小さな巨人は
何回でも跳んでた≫
≪あのときは
よく分かんなかたけど
I didn't really understand it at the time,
きとあれが仲間からの
信頼というやつだたんだ≫
but now I think that's what it means to have the faith of your teammates.
I'm counting on you, Asahi.
≪この人なら決めてくれると
チムのみんなが思てたから
Everyone on the team believed that he could score the point,
みんなが
あの小さなエスに繋いだんだ≫
so they all worked to get the ball to their little ace.
≪そんできと
旭さんもそれと同じだ≫
I'm sure that it's the same for Asahi.
おい
エスすげぇな
Hey—
The ace is amazing!
ブロクいてもいなくても
It doesn't matter if they're blocking or not, 'cause he can blast through 'em anyway!
あんなふうにぶち抜けるんなら
関係ないもんな
なんだよ
What is it?
Nothing.
別に
ん
Neighborhood Assoc.       Karasuno
(嶋田)カバ
(菅原)前前
Cover it!
Forward!
レフト
Left!
If I had his height and power, I could be like him.
≪あんなふうな身長とか
パワがあたら俺も
The left is coming! Firm up defense!
Hinata, go further back!
No, the Little Giant was amazing for his size.
≪いやいや小さな巨人は
小さいけどすごかたんだ≫
≪けど
Still...
≪いいなぁ≫
I wish.
Hinata!
日向
あ
ガン
あば
(２人)あ
ぎゃあ
(東峰)日向
うぅ
Hinata?
(西谷)あ生きてる
(田中)大丈夫か
Hey, he's alive.
You okay?
You okay?! I'm so sorry!
(月島)どう考えても
ﾎﾞｹとしてたこいつが悪いでしょ
Any way you slice it, it's his fault for standing there like a putz.
きゅきゅ救急
落ち着けよ先生
F-F-F-First aid...
Calm down, teach.
あ大丈夫ですすみません
(澤村)ほんとか
I'm all right. I'm sorry.
Really?! Maybe you should sit out to be on the safe side.
念のために休憩を
ほほんとに大丈夫です
I-I'm really all right!
I didn't dodge it in time, that's all. It's nothing serious.
ちょとかわしきれなかただけで
大したことは
I'm used to taking it in the face.
顔面受け慣れてるし
(菅原)慣れるなよ
That's not a good thing.
あ
(２人)ん
Why were you daydreaming during a match?
何ボケとしてた試合中に
あうあぁ
≪やべぇ影山がどならない
マジ怒りだ≫
Crap. Kageyama isn't shouting, which means he's really mad.
≪後頭部に
サブぶつけたときの感じだ≫
It's like the time I served the ball into the back of his head.
I know what you're thinking.
俺は知てるぞ
｢エスはカコいいけど
Being an ace is cool.
Being a decoy can't be my best weapon. That's stupid and lame.
自分のいちばんの武器は囮なんて
地味でカコ悪い
自分に東峰さんみたいな
タパとパワがあれば
You wish you were as tall and powerful as Azumane so you could be the ace!
エスになれるのに｣
ぐ
I-I don't think that!
そそんなこと思てない
くもないけど
Most of the time.
Now that you know there's an ace, you not only dream about being him, you're jealous of him!
エスがいるて分かてから
興味とか憧れのほかに
嫉妬してただろ
う
試合中に
余計なこと考えてんじゃねぇよ
Clear your head of that kind of garbage during a match!
羨ましくて何が悪いんだ
What's wrong with being jealous?
もともとでかいお前になんか
絶対分かんないんだよ
You've always been tall,
so you could never know what it's like!
おい
≪こらバレ部
Hey!
Hey, you. Volleyball team.
そろそろ終了の時間だぞ
It's time to shut it down. You need to put this away.
早く片づけを
すみません
I'm sorry! We need to finish this match.
この試合が終わるまで
あでも時間が
But it's late.
I'll be responsible for locking it up.
(武田)
僕が責任を持て閉めますので
≪俺のせいで中断さしたのに
It's my fault the match got interrupted.
影山にどなてしまた
And I made Kageyama shout at me.
じゃあ
無理言てすいません
All right.
Thanks for putting up with me.
(澤村)先生すみません
Sir, I'm sorry!
ありがとうございます
(田中)武ちゃんカコいい
Thank you so much.
Take, that's bitchin'!
(澤村)よしじゃあ続き始めよう
(一同)おす
Okay, let's resume the match!
Yessir!
Neighborhood Assoc.       Karasuno
(菅原)一本
(内沢)ナイサ
Let's score!
Give us a good one!
(田中)よしゃ来いや
Okay, I'm ready for you.
(滝ノ上)
お高校生チムは今
Hey, this is the most powerful attack rotation for the high schooler team.
攻撃力が
いちばん高いロテかな
あのチビコの速攻には
気ぃつけないとな
We have to watch out for the short guy's fast attack.
はい
あの
Right.
Excuse me.
次こいつにトス上げるんで
My next set will be to him.
全力でブロクしてください
Please block him as best you can.
Haikyuu !!
次こいつにトス上げるんで
全力でブロクしてください
My next set will be to him.
Please block him as best you can.
(滝ノ上･東峰)え
(滝ノ上)なんだぁ挑発か
What's this, a dare?
Yes, it's a dare.
はい挑発です
なめたマネしてすみません
Forgive me for acting like a snot.
(滝ノ上)ははは
なんだお前面白ぇな
You're a funny guy!
よしゃ挑発乗たるぜ
Okay! Let's do this dare!
Thank you!
あざす
(繋心)何考えてんだ
What is he thinking?
Fast attacks are effective because they're unpredictable.
速攻はあくまで
予測不能だから有効なんであて
There's no way Peewee can take a
head-on block with the cards on the table.
手の内さらしてブロクと
真向勝負てなたら
ちんちくりんに勝ち目ねぇだろ
そうですね
You're right.
We've gotta stop them.
真向勝負になたら
そうかもしれないですね
I would have to agree, if he took them head-on.
Yeah! We can't let them make monkeys of us.
≪何なんだよクソ影山≫
What's that idiot thinking?
Why tell them our next attack?
≪わざわざ
次の攻撃教えてどうすんだよ≫
≪あんなでかいブロク
俺じゃ打ち抜けないのに≫
I can't spike through their huge blockers!
今のお前は
ん
Right now,
ただのちょとジｬンプ力があて
素早いだけの下手くそだ
you're nothing but a klutzy shit who happens to be nimble and can jump high.
大黒柱のエスになんかなれねぇ
う
You will never be the breadwinner ace.
(田中)おい
(東峰)ちょちょい
Hey.
J-Just a minute.
But...
as long as I'm around, you're the greatest!
俺がいればお前は最強だ
え
Huh?
東峰さんのスパイクは
すげぇ威力があて
Azumane's spikes are so forceful, he can cut through a triple block.
３枚ブロクだて打ち抜ける
えいやでも毎回じゃないし
Uh, but not every time. I, uh...
動揺しすぎす
じゃあお前はどうだ
You're getting too flustered.
Now how about you?
When I set for you, have you ever been stopped by blockers?
俺がトスを上げたときお前は
ブロｯクに捕またことがあるか
(滝ノ上)ナイサ
Give us a good serve!
オライ
(澤村)ナイスレシブ
Got it!
Nice receive!
≪ブロクでかい
The blockers are too tall!
かわせ
あ
Go around!
What else can you do, you moron?!
それ以外にできることあんのか
ボケェ
≪打ち抜けないなら
If I can't break through...
かわす
go around!
はあ
あ
≪ブロク嫌だ
止められるのは嫌だ
I hate being blocked.
I hate being stopped!
≪目の前にブロクがいたら
俺に勝ち目なんかない≫
I don't stand a chance of winning with blockers in front of me.
≪エスみたいな戦い方が
できない≫
I can't take them on the same way the ace does.
≪でも
But...
≪俺がいれば
As long as I'm around...
≪お前は最強だ
you're the greatest!
(嶋田)う
お前はエスじゃないけど
You aren't the ace!
But with your speed and jumping ability
and my sets, you can take on any blockers!
そのスピドとバネと
俺のトスがあれば
どんなブロクとだて
勝負できる
エスが打ち抜いた１点も
お前がかわして決めた１点も
The ace blasts through for a point.
You go around for a point.
同じ１点だ
A point is a point!
｢エス｣て冠が
付いてなくても
You don't need the ace's crown.
You can hammer out more points than anyone!
お前は誰よりも
たくさんの得点をたたき出して
だからこそ
敵はお前をマクして
That's why, thanks to your decoy skills, our opponents will be marking you, freeing up our other spikers!
ほかのスパイカは
お前の囮のおかげで自由になる
エスもだ
Including the ace!
Right?!
ね
(田中)おうおうおうそうだぞ
Yeah?
Yeah, listen to him!
お前の囮が
あるのとないのとじゃ
Your decoy work drastically affects our success rate.
俺たちの決定率が全然違うんだぞ
それでもお前は
Do you still believe that your job is uncool?!
今の自分の役割が
カコ悪いと思うのか
思わない
ああ
I don't.
What?!
思わない
I don't!
よし
(菅原)あはは
Good!
今の一発すごかた
That last hit was incredible.
練習中断さして
すみませんでした
I'm sorry for interrupting our practice match!
Uh, sure.
(澤村)あうん
すみませんでした
I'm sorry!
Please continue the match, sir!
試合の続き
(２人)お願いします
Sir!
(田中)
おしゃ一気に追い上げるぞ
Okay, we're gonna seriously catch up!
Right!
先生
ん
Teach?
Just because you happened to nail that one, don't keep jumping in the same direction.
(繋心)あの二人
(武田)日向君と影山君ですか
About those two...
Do you mean Hinata and Kageyama?
同じ中学出身か
それとも小学校から一緒とか
Are they from the same junior high? Or the same grade school?
えいやいや彼らは
この前会たばかりですよ
Huh?
Not at all. Those two only just met.
It was a real mess at first because they didn't get along.
最初は馬が合わずに
大変だたみたいで
あ烏養君
Ukai?
(繋心)非情だな
That's cruel.
バチ
(澤村･田中･日向)よしゃ
Yeah!
Neighborhood Assoc.       Karasuno
These high schoolers are pretty good.
なかなかやるなぁ高校生
おさんも
本気出しちゃうんだぜ
Us middle aged guys are gonna have to show our stuff.
≪ジャンプフロタ
A jump float!
Hinata!
(田中)日向
よしゃオライ
All right! I got it!
あボェ
ははは見たか
大人気ねぇ
See that?
That's immature.
What is that?
特にすごい威力のサブ
て感じじゃないようでしたけど
That serve didn't look like it had much momentum.
ジャンプフロタサブだ
That is a jump float serve.
無回転で打つことで
ボルの軌道がブレるんだ
Serving it without any spin gives the ball a shaky trajectory.
急に曲がたり落ちたりな
It can swerve and drop without warning.
It's like a knuckleball. That's so cool!
ま魔球みたいですね
カコいい
(山口)あ
(清水)山口そち得点
Yamaguchi, that's your point.
ああすみません
Oh, sorry.
(森)もう一本
One more!
うわちょあ
ピ
Hey, watch it!
あ
ピ
Neighborhood Assoc.       Karasuno
(縁下)うわ
(嶋田)よしゃ
Yes!
(繋心)これで４点目
This is the 4th point in a row.
The first-year combo attack is impressive,
１年生コンビの攻撃はすごいが
とにもかくにもレシブだな
What happened to all that enthusiasm, high schoolers?
but the first-years and second-years' receives need work.
That's match point!
特に１２年
一気に頂きます
You're all mine!
(澤村)く
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
(滝ノ上)
今度は逃がさねぇぜチビコ
You won't get away with it this time, Shorty!
捉えた
Caught him!
やべ
ぬあ
Oh no!
どうもご無沙汰してます
(西谷)く
Hello! Remember me?!
(田中)なぬ
(菅原)ナイス西谷
What?!
Nice, Nishinoya!
Suga!
(東峰)スガ
(菅原)旭
Asahi!
ピ
Neighborhood Assoc.       Karasuno
Damn. I'm sorry, Hinata!
くそすまん日向
完璧に俺フリだたのに
I was totally wide open too!
えいえ
けどすげぇぜ
Th-That's okay.
But that was amazing.
見事に全員お前につられてたぞ
逆に悔しいくらいだ
You had them all dogging after you.
It almost made me jealous.
次も頼むぜ
おおす
I'll be counting on you next time!
Y-Yessir!
I don't know what just happened,
but that made me feel young again.
(嶋田)いやよく分かんないけど
青春だたなぁ
｢トスを呼んでくれエス｣
とかねぇ青春いいねぇ
"Please call for a set, ace!"
It's great to be young!
(森)｢俺がいればお前は最強だ｣
とか言てみてぇ
"With me around, you're the greatest!" I wish I could say that!
高校生かけぇ
High schoolers sure are cool!
You made us old timers feel like yesterday's news!
(滝ノ上)俺らおさん組の
置いてけぼり感ときたら
(菅原)すすみません
S-Sorry, sir.
(滝ノ上)なんつうかまだ
いろいろバラバラな感じだけど
How can I say it?
You guys haven't got it together yet, but once you do pull together, I think you guys are going places.
ちゃんとまとまたら
いいとこまで行けんじゃねぇか
お前ら
(一同)おお
(澤村)ありがとうございました
(一同)あざした
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
(繋心)とにかくレシブだ
それができなきゃ始まんねぇ
Anyway, receiving! You can't get anywhere without that.
明日からみちりやるからな
(一同)おす
We'll be training those fully tomorrow!
Yessir!
(澤村)あざした
(一同)した
Thank you, sir!
Sir!
おうストレチサボんなよ
Hey, don't skip the stretches.
Stretch!
(澤村)ストレチ
(一同)おす
Yessir!
(澤村)ゆくり回せ
はぁ
Rotate slowly!
そんなに
レシブひどかたですかね
Is their receiving really that bad? Bad enough to sigh about?
ため息が出るほどに
いやそれは置いといてだな
No, setting that aside.
自分がプレヤとして
選ばれる側にいた頃は
I never gave it much thought when I was up for selection,
考えもしなかたが
but the one doing the selecting has a tough job.
選ぶ側つうのも
いろいろ悩むもんだよな
Equipment Room
(澤村)片づけ急げよ
(山口)おす
Get it all put away!
Yessir!
(西谷)山口ポルそち持て
(山口)はい
Yamaguchi, bring the balls over there.
Right!
Okay. One, two...
旭さん
ん
Asahi?
俺はエスじゃないけど
I'm no ace...
エスの前に
道を作ることはできます
but I can clear a path for the ace!
最強の囮になります
I'll become the greatest decoy!
あか影山のトスがないと
できないけど
A-Although, I can't do that without Kageyama's sets.
だからだからえと
So, what I'm trying to say is...
"Give it your best!" doesn't sound right.
≪｢頑張てください｣は
なんか違うかな≫
"Let's give it our best!" sounds kind of snotty.
≪｢頑張りましょう｣は
なんか生意気な感じだ≫
Hinata?
(東峰)日向だけ
Is that your name?
エスてさ
大抵ウイングスパイカの
The ace is basically the name given to the left wing spiker, which makes him me or Tanaka.
レフトのポジションの選手が
そう呼ばれるけど
俺とか田中とか
はい
Yes.
It's definitely the ace's job to break through triple blocks and to receive delivery of sets when the timing is crucial.
３枚ブロクを
ぶち抜けるとか
大事なところで
トスが集まるとか
それは
確かにエスの役目だけど
((そのスピドとバネと
俺のトスがあれば
With your speed and jumping ability and my sets, you can take on any blockers!
どんなブロクとだて
勝負できる
あんなふうにセタに
言わせられるていうのも
I think that having a setter say something like that to you is awesome.
とんでもなく
すごいことだと思うよ
ん
えとだからあのなんだ
Anyway, what I'm saying is,
no matter what name the position is given,
どんな呼び名でも
ポジションでも
敵チムに
いちばん恐れられる選手が
I'd say that the player that terrifies the opposing team the most has to be the coolest.
いちばんカｯコいいと思わないか
Like, "Look out for that middle blocker! He's crazy." Things like that.
｢あのミドルブロカやべぇぞ
気ぃつけろ｣とか言われてさ
Yeah, yeah.
負けないからな
I'm not gonna lose.
Yessir!
あでも俺はレギュラに
戻してもらえたらの話だけど
But that's only if I'm allowed back into the starting lineup.
Asahi, you sure are timid for such a big guy.
旭はでかいくせに
ほんと気は小さいなぁ
ちゃんと
お前も復活したなスガ
You're back in action, Suga.
(菅原)うじうじ
くよくよいじいじしてて
I apologize for worrying and obsessing.
すみませんでした
そこまで言てない
I didn't say that.
頼れる西谷も戻てきたし
おす
And the reliable Nishinoya is back too.
Yessir!
でも教頭突き飛ばしたりするのは
二度となしね
But you can never shove the Vice Principal ever again.
ああと
名ばかりのエスの
I suppose our timid wing blocker,
the ace in name alone, is also back.
へなちょこウイングスパイカも
戻てきてたなぁそういえば
Now that I think about it.
え
パン
Okay, get this thing locked down and go home!
じゃあ
一発締めてととと上がれ
(澤村)烏野ファイ
Karasuno... fight!
Yeah!
There are so many dreams that can definitely come true
I always sat somewhere, downcast, dejected, depressed,
but still I decided I would fight,
and not let all my frustration go to waste
This is our revenge
Next Episode Preview
It's finally time for training camp.
(田中)とうとう合宿だな
(西谷)おう
Yeah. Under one roof with Kiyoko.
潔子さんと一つ屋根の下龍
Ryuu!
(田中)ノヤさん
(西谷)龍
Noya!
Ryuu!
(田中)ノヤさん
ああの一体何が
Noya!
Um, what's going on?
Ryuu!
(清水)ほときなさい
(西谷)龍
Noya!
Ignore them.
Ryuu!
Episode Eleven:
The Decision
Noya!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Ryuu!
"The Decision."
Noya!